CLINT EASTWOOD...the deadliest man alive...takes on a whole
army with two guns and a fistful of dynamite!
Two Mules for Sister Sara is a western, adventure,
romance film directed by Don Siegel.
When a wandering mercenary named Hogan rescues a nun called Sister Sara from the unwanted attentions of
a band of rogues on the Mexican plains, he has no idea what he has let himself in for.
Their chance encounter results in the blowing up of a train and a French garrison, as
well as igniting a spark between them that survives a shocking discovery.
Sara, played by Shirley MacLaine.
Hogan, played by Clint Eastwood.
Colonel Beltran, played by Manolo Fábregas.
General LeClaire, played by Alberto Morin.
1st American, played by Armando Silvestre.
2nd American, played by John Kelly.
Two Mules for Sister Sara is a 1970 American-Mexican Western film in Panavision directed by Don Siegel and
starring Shirley MacLaine and Clint Eastwood set during the French intervention in Mexico (1861–1867).
The film was to have been the first in a five-year exclusive association
between Universal Pictures and Sanen Productions of Mexico.
It was the second of five collaborations between Siegel and
Eastwood, following Coogan's Bluff (1968).
The collaboration continued with The Beguiled and Dirty Harry
(both 1971) and finally Escape from Alcatraz (1979).
The plot follows an American mercenary who gets mixed up with a nun and aids a group of
Juarista rebels during the puppet reign of Emperor Maximilian in Mexico.
The film featured both American and Mexican actors and actresses, including being
filmed in the picturesque countryside near Tlayacapan, Morelos.
Ennio Morricone composed the film's music.
Two Mules for Sister Sara was a moderate financial success
and received a warm critical reception.
The film explores themes of gunslinger, brothel, mexican
revolution, treasure hunt, execution.
The tone is emotional.